IWW Records 5210
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Lewis, Austin. "Proletarian and Petit-Bourgeois." Chicago: I.W.W. Publishing Bureau, no date. 47 pages. And Russell, Charles Edward. "What Comes of Playing the Game." 13 pages and Nearing, Scott. "Those Who Own and Those Who Work." 14 pages., Publication (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Item 2: Proletarian and Petit-Bourgeois., Publication (Box 14, Folder 19)
    Notes: 48 pages. Includes What Comes of Playing the Game and Those Who Own and Those Who Work
  - Item 3: What Comes of Playing the Game, Publication (Box 14, Folder 19)
    Author: Charles Edward Russell
    Notes: Bound with Proletarian and Petit- Bourgeois
  - Item 4: Those Who Own and Those Who Work., Publication (Box 14, Folder 19)
    Author: Scott Nearing
- MacDonald, J.A. "Unemployment and the Machine." Chicago: I.W.W. 1925. 94 pages and 1934 edition 45 pages., 1925-1934 (Box 14, Folder 20)
  1925, 1934
  - Item 1: Unemployment and the Machine., 1925; Publication (Box 14, Folder 20)
    Author: J. A. MacDonald
  - Item 2: Unemployment and the Machine., 1934; Publication (Box 14, Folder 20)
    Notes: Second edition.
- Magnes, Judah L. "Amnesty for Political Prisoners." New York: National Civil Liberties Bureau, 1919. 23 pages., Publication (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - Item 1: Amenesty for Political Prisoners., 1919; Publication (Box 14, Folder 21)
    Author: Judah L. Magnes
    Notes: Address delivered in Washington, DC, on April 1917, 1919
- Marcy, Mary E. "Shop Talks on Economics." Chicago: I.W.W., 1921. 37 pages., Publication (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - Item 1: Shop Talks on Economics., 1921; Publication (Box 14, Folder 22)
    Author: Mary E. Marcy
  - Item 2: Shop Talks on Economics., 1921; Publication (Box 14, Folder 22)
- Monoldi, Peo. "Why Building Workers Must Organize in the One Big Union." Chicago, no date. 16 pages., Publication (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - Item 1: Ol' Rags An' Bottles., 1919; Publication (Box 14, Folder 23)
- National Civil Liberties Bureau. "Ol' Rags An' Bottles." New York: National Civil Liberties Bureau, 1919. 7 pages., Publication (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - Item 1: Why Building Workers Must organize in One Big Union., Publication (Box 14, Folder 24)
    Author: Peo Monold
- National Civil Liberties Bureau. "The Truth About the I.W.W.: Facts In Relations to the Trial at Chicago by Competent Industrial Investigators and Noted Economists." New York, 1918. 55 pages., Publication (Box 14, Folder 25)
  - Item 1: The Truth About the I.W.W.: Facts In Relations to the Trial at Chicago by Competent Industrial Investigators and Noted Economists., 1918; Publication (Box 14, Folder 25)
    Author: National Civil Liberties Bureau.
  - Item 2: The Truth About the I.W.W.: Facts In Relations to the Trial at Chicago by Competent Industrial Investigators and Noted Economists., 1918; Publication (Box 14, Folder 25)
  - Item 3: The Truth About the I.W.W.: Facts In Relations to the Trial at Chicago by Competent Industrial Investigators and Noted Economists., 1918; Publication (Box 14, Folder 25)
  - Item 4: The Truth About the I.W.W.: Facts In Relations to the Trial at Chicago by Competent Industrial Investigators and Noted Economists., 1918; Publication (Box 14, Folder 25)
  - Item 5: The Truth About the I.W.W.: Facts In Relations to the Trial at Chicago by Competent Industrial Investigators and Noted Economists., 1918; Publication (Box 14, Folder 25)
- Nearing, Scott. See: Lewis, A., Publication (Box 14, Folder 26)
  - Item 1: Strike Strategy., Publication (Box 14, Folder 26)
    Author: National Rank and File Movement.
- One Big Union Club. "History of '400' A.W.O. The One Big Union Idea In Action." New York: 1939. 23 pages., Publication (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Item 1: History of "400" A.W.O. The One Big Union Idea In Action., 1939; Publication (Box 15, Folder 1)
    Author: One Big Union Club.
  - Item 2: History of "400" A.W.O. The One Big Union Idea In Action., 1939; Publication (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Item 3: History of "400" A.W.O. The One Big Union Idea In Action., 1939; Publication (Box 15, Folder 1)
- One Big Union Club. "Why One Big Union?" New York, 1936. 10 pages., Publication (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Item 1: Why One Big Union?, 1936; Publication (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Item 2: Why One Big Union?, 1936; Publication (Box 15, Folder 2)
- Perry, Grover H. "The Revolutionary I.W.W." Cleveland: I.W.W. Publishing Bureau, 1916. 11 pages. And "How Scabs Are Bred." 4 pages. And Williams, B.H. "The Constructive Program of the I.W.W." 9 pages., Publication (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Item 1: The Revolutionary I.W.W., 1913; Publication (Box 15, Folder 3)
    Author: Grover H. Perry
  - Item 2: The Revolutionary I.W.W., 1916; Publication (Box 15, Folder 3)
    Notes: Includes How Scabs Are Bred and The Constructive Program of the IWW
  - Item 3: How Scabs Are Bred., 1913; Publication (Box 15, Folder 3)
    Notes: Bound with The Revolutionary IWW
  - Item 4: How Scabs Are Bred., 1916; Publication (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Item 5: The Constructive Program of the I.W.W, 1913; Publication (Box 15, Folder 3)
    Author: B. H. Williams
  - Item 6: The Constructive Program of the I.W.W, 1916; Publication (Box 15, Folder 3)
- "The Right to His Day in Court: Shall Lawyers Defend Those Deemed to be Adversaries of Our Government." New York: National Civil Liberties Bureau, 1919. 11 pages., Publication (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Item 1: The Right to His Day In Court: Shall Lawyers Defend Those Deemed To Be Adversaries of Our Government., 1919; Publication (Box 15, Folder 4)
    Author: Arthur Le Sueur; George Chase
- Rowan, James. "The I.W.W. in the Lumber Industry." Chicago: I.W.W., no date. 52 pages., Publication (Box 15, Folder 5)
  missing
  - Item 1: Industrial Unionism and the I.W.W., Publication (Box 15, Folder 5)
    Author: Vincent St.John
  - Item 2: Industrial Unionism and the I.W.W., Publication (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Item 3: Industrial Unionism and the I.W.W., Publication (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Item 4: Unionismo Industrial La I. W. W., Publication (Box 15, Folder 5)
- Russell, Charles E. See: Lewis, A., Publication (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Item 1: The I.W.W.: Its History, Structure and Methods., 1911; Publication (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Item 2: The I.W.W.: Its History, Structure and Methods., 1917; Publication (Box 15, Folder 6)
    Notes: Revised
  - Item 3: The I.W.W.: Its History, Structure and Methods., 1917; Publication (Box 15, Folder 6)
    Notes: Revised. Copy 2.
  - Item 4: The I.W.W.: Its History, Structure and Methods., 1919; Publication (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Item 5: The I.W.W.: Its History, Structure and Methods., 1919; Publication (Box 15, Folder 6)
- St. John Vincent. "Industrial Unionism and the I.W.W." New Castle, Pennsylvania: I.W.W. Publishing Bureau, no date. 16 pages., Publication (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Item 1: Letters to Judd, An American Workingman., 1949; Publication (Box 15, Folder 7)
    Author: Upton Sinclair
    Notes: New and Revised edition
- St. John, Vincent. "The I.W.W.: Its History, Structure, and Methods." New Castle, Pennsylvania: I.W.W. Publishing Bureau, 1911. 23 pages. (Also 1917 - 32 pages; 1919 - 47 pages.), 1911-1919 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  1911, 1917, 1919
  - Item 1: Starving Admidst Too Much., Publication (Box 15, Folder 8)
    Author: T-Bone Slim
- Sinclair, Upton. "Letters to Judd, An American Workingman." Gerard, Kansas, 1949. 64 pages., Publication (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Item 1: Their Court and Our Class., Publication (Box 15, Folder 9)
    Author: Walker C. Smith
- Slim, T-Bone. "Starving Amidst Too Much." Chicago: I.W.W. Foodstuff Workers, 38 pages., Publication (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Item 1: Was It Murder?: Authentic Record of the Causes Leading to the Actual Events of, and the Trial That Followed the Armistice Day Tragedy at Centralia, Wash., 1919; Publication (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Item 2: Was It Murder?: Authentic Record of the Causes Leading to the Actual Events of, and the Trial That Followed the Armistice Day Tragedy at Centralia, Wash., 1919; Publication (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Item 3: Was It Murder?: Authentic Record of the Causes Leading to the Actual Events of, and the Trial That Followed the Armistice Day Tragedy at Centralia, Wash., 1919; Publication (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Item 4: Was It Murder?: Authentic Record of the Causes Leading to the Actual Events of, and the Trial That Followed the Armistice Day Tragedy at Centralia, Wash., 1922; Publication (Box 15, Folder 10)
- Smith, Walker C. "Their Court and Our Class." Seattle, Washington, no date. 16 pages., Publication (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Item 1: Union-Smashing in Sacramento., 1935; Publication (Box 15, Folder 11)
    Author: Herbert Solow; Samuel S. White; Travers Clements
- Smith, Walker C. "Was It Murder?" I.W.W. Centralia Committee, 1919. 47 pages., Publication (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Item 1: Library Bulletin. No. 25. "The State of Idaho vs. William D. Haywood, Jan.-Feb. 1960., Publication (Box 15, Folder 12)
    Author: Tamiment Institute Library.
- Smith, Walker C. "Was It Murder? Authentic Record of the Causes Leading to the Actual Events of, and the Trial that Followed the Armistice Day Tragedy at Centralia, Washington." Seattle: Northwest District Defense Committee, 1922. 48 pages., Publication (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Item 1: Truth About Butte: A Little History for Thoughtful People., 1917; Publication (Box 15, Folder 13)
    Author: George R. Tompkins
- Solow, Herbert. "Union Smashing In Sacramento." New York: National Sacramento Appeal Committee, 1935. 31 pages., Publication (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Item 1: World Labor Needs a Union., 1969; Publication (Box 15, Folder 14)
    Author: Fred Thompson
- Tamiment Institute Library. Library Bulletin. Number 25. "The State of Idaho vs. William D. Haywood," January-February 1960. New York, 1960. 18 page mimeo., Publication (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Item 1: On the Duty of Civil Disobedience., 1963; Publication (Box 15, Folder 15)
    Author: Henry David Thoreau; Gene Sharp
  - Item 2: On the Duty of Civil Disobedience., 1963; Publication (Box 15, Folder 15)
- Tompkins, George R. "Truth About Butte: A Little History for Thoughtful People." Butte, Montana: 1917. 32 pages, Publication (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Item 1: Handbook of Industrial Unionism and Analysis of the Preamble by A.S. Edwards., Publication (Box 15, Folder 16)
    Author: William E. Trautmann; A. S. Edwards
    Notes: Second edition, Revised.
  - Item 2: Handbook of Industrial Unionism and Analysis of the Preamble by A.S. Edwards., Publication (Box 15, Folder 16)
    Notes: Third edition.
- Trautmann, William E. "Handbook of Industrial Unionism and analysis of the Preamble by A.S. Edwards." Chicago: I.W.W., no date. (2 editions) 32 pages and 34 pages., Publication (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Item 1: One Big Union: An Outline of a Possible Industrial Organization of the Working Class, with Chart., Publication (Box 15, Folder 17)
    Author: William E. Trautmann
- Trautman, William E. "One Big Union: An Outline of a Possible Industrial Organization of the Working Class, with Chart." Chicago: Charles H. Kerr and Company, no date. 31 pages., Publication (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Item 1: One Great Union., Publication (Box 15, Folder 18)
    Notes: Fifth edition, Revised. Contains fold-out chart.
  - Item 2: One Great Union., Publication (Box 15, Folder 18)
    Notes: Fifth edition, Revised. Fold-out chart missing.
- Trautmann, William E. "One Great Union." Detroit: I.W.W., Literature and Education Bureau, no date. 31 pages., Publication (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Item 1: Why Strikes are lost; How to Win., Publication (Box 15, Folder 19)
- "The Truth About the I.W.W. Prisoners." New York: American Civil Liberties Union, 1922. 47 pages., Publication (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - Item 1: The Truth About the I.W.W. Prisoners., 1922; Publication (Box 15, Folder 20)
- Varney, Harold Lord. "Industrial Communism - The I.W.W." no publisher, no date. 24 pages., Publication (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - Item 1: Industrial Communism: The I.W.W., Publication (Box 15, Folder 21)
    Author: Harold Lord Varney
  - Item 2: Industrial Communism: The I.W.W., Publication (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - Item 3: Industrial Communism: The I.W.W., Publication (Box 15, Folder 21)
- Varney, Harold Lord. "The One Big Union - As It Is." no publisher, no date. 16 pages., Publication (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - Item 1: The One Big Union - As It Is., Publication (Box 15, Folder 22)
- Walklin, Frank. "A Fair Trial? A Record of the Prejudice and Passion that Dominated the Legal Profession and the Press in the Famous Centralia Labor Case." no publisher, 1920. 15 pages., Publication (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - Item 1: A Fair Trial? A Record of the Prejudice and Passion that Dominated the Legal Profession and the Press in the Famous Centralia Labor Case., 1920; Publication (Box 15, Folder 23)
    Author: Frank Walklin
- "The War on the Colorado Miners." New York: American Civil Liberties Union, 1928. 12 pages., Publication (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - Item 1: The War on the Colorado Miners., 1928; Publication (Box 15, Folder 24)
- Williams, B.H. "Eleven Blind Leaders or 'Practical Socialism' and 'Revolutionary Tactics'." New Castle, Pennsylvania: I.W.W. Publishing Bureau, 1910. 29 pages., Publication (Box 15, Folder 25)
  - Item 1: Eleven Blind Leaders or "Practical Socialism" and "Revolutionary Tactics.", 1910; Publication (Box 15, Folder 25)
  - Item 2: Eleven Blind Leaders or "Practical Socialism" and "Revolutionary Tactics.", 1910; Publication (Box 15, Folder 25)
  - Item 3: Eleven Blind Leaders or "Practical Socialism" and "Revolutionary Tactics.", 1910; Publication (Box 15, Folder 25)
- Williams, B.H. See also: Perry, Grover., Publication (Box 15, Folder 26)
  - Item 1: The First Congress of the Red Trade Union International at Moscow, 1921., 1922; Publication (Box 15, Folder 26)
    Author: George Williams
  - Item 2: The First Congress of the Red Trade Union International at Moscow, 1921., 1922; Publication (Box 15, Folder 26)
    Notes: Second edition, Revised. Copy 2.
- Williams, George. "The First Congress of the Red Trade Union International at Moscow, 1921." Chicago: I.W.W., no date. 60 pages., Publication (Box 15, Folder 27)
  - Item 1: New Life to the New Land., 1942; Publication (Box 15, Folder 27)
    Author: George Woodcock
- Woodruff, Abner E. "The Advancing Proletariat: A Study of the Movement of the Working Class from Wage Slavery to Freedom." Cleveland: I.W.W. Publishing Bureau, 1914 and 1919. 32 pages., 1914-1919 (Box 15, Folder 28)
  1914 and 1919
  - Item 1: The Advancing Proletariat: A Study of the Movement of the Working Class From Wage Slavery to Freedom., 1919; Publication (Box 15, Folder 28)
    Author: Abner E. Woodruff
  - Item 2: The Advancing Proletariat: A Study of the Movement of the Working Class From Wage Slavery to Freedom., 1914; Publication (Box 15, Folder 28)
- Woodruff, Abner E. "The Evolution of Industrial Democracy." Chicago: I.W.W., no date. 45 pages., Publication (Box 15, Folder 29)
  - Item 1: The Evolution of Industrial Democracy., Publication (Box 15, Folder 29)
  - Item 2: The Evolution of Industrial Democracy., Publication (Box 15, Folder 29)
  - Item 3: The Evolution of Industrial Democracy., Publication (Box 15, Folder 29)
- "Workers of the World Unite!" Chicago, no date. 36 pages., Publication (Box 15, Folder 30)
  - Item 1: Workers of the World Unite!, Publication (Box 15, Folder 30)
- The One Big Union Structure poster -, Publication (Box 19)
- The One Big Union Structure Poster, Publication (Box 20)
- Images digitized from the collection., Publication (Box 21)